Contact

+91 9068022496 (Mobile) saadjamal4786@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/saad-jamal (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Entrepreneurship Leadership Marketing Strategy

Languages

English (Professional Working)
Hindi (Native or Bilingual)
Urdu (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Business Analyst
Influencing People
Logical Reasoning
Stock Market Basics
Numerical Reasoning

Honors-Awards
LIC-Student of the Year
Rising Talent
Jr. IDP Winner

Publications

Exposure, Opportunities & Excellence

#Saad Jamal#

Budding Entrepreneur| Director International Services| Senior Marketing Analyst

Mumbai

Summary

Welcome to the Reality Distortion Field.#

Come with a Problem, Leave with a Plan!

I specialize in Organic growth & Marketing for early stage startups.

I dream to design the most user friendly products ever made on planet Earth so that I can market them with all my might to reach every potential customer. I dream.

I'm Dedicated to Work. Determined to Grow and Destined to be very very Successful!#

I imagine. I innovate. I improve. And I will Inspire.#

It's the Best Time to Invest in Me. And, it will be true always.

I'm passionate about problems. I believe they're the opportunities to Grow. My Passion to Learn and Dedication to Work are the reasons for my High Self-confidence.

Having a Mentor like Mr. David Wagstaff adds another level of Self belief.

You can trust my Analytical skills & Critical Thinking. I'm really good with numbers. Check out my scores:)

You can share your challenges and I would love to solve them for you or your Startup/Business/Company/Project.

I assure you for confidentiality of your information. Ethics, Honesty, Truthfulness, a tested EQ of 135 and a pinch of Humor (sometimes sarcasm) are my Secret ingredients for life long healthy relationships. (Let's keep it a secret between us)

I am ready and would be glad to help all deserving ones.

I have a Good enough Network of Entrepreneurs which have something for everyone.

If you have reached this point you might be interested further.

Feel free to connect with me! I'm always there online/offline for meeting amazing people like you!

Thanks & regards, Saad Jamal

Experience

Entrepreneur's Network 1 year 6 months

Senior Marketing Analyst March 2020 - Present (6 months)

Grand Rapids, Michigan, United States (Remote)

#

Hereby, I got one of my favorite projects of Monitoring Google Analytics & consulting on future marketing strategies based on data analysis. It requires analytical skills with a clear strategic approach.

Other Key Responsibilities which I enjoy are:

Branding Entrepreneur's Network over LinkedIn where I have achieved 3 times better engagement rate in just a week & 18% more followers organically.

Encephage advertising to get better leads.

Facebook advertising to get better leads

Marketing Analyst
March 2019 - March 2020 (1 year 1 month)
Grand Rapids, Michigan, USA (Remote)

I'm achieving a reach of 2.5k per post organically on average. This is fairly high as we have around 280 followers only.

As compared to Facebook Ads, Facebook Ads on our page have a reach of just around few hundreds for \$30. I'm proud to claim a 15 times more reach with our highest reach which had a reach of 4.6k.

I am a part of this Wonderful Venture since very beginning as a freelancer. I am gaining a fair experience for establishing similar ventures.

Working closely with David over Marketing, I am currently working on the Facebook project. My responsibilities included establishing a Facebook page and manage it. I sincerely thank David to allow me Independence and authority to manage it on my own.

Product Manager

May 2019 - July 2019 (3 months)

Grand Rapids, Michigan, United States (Remote)

I'm being promoted to 'Product Manager' at Entrepreneur's Network for a couple of months during my vacations. Although, I will continue my work of Social Media Marketing.

My Roles and Responsibilities include:

- 1) Help organising the Webinars.
- 2) Communication with Speakers participants, clients about upcoming programs for which they have registered.
- 3) Program managing will also include adding some content on our website about the events.
- 4) It also includes co-developing future programs with Founder and Managing Principal, Mr. David Wastaffe and helping to manage those details.
- 6) Managing Social Media handles and Content Marketing as I did before.

Rotaract Director International Services April 2020 - Present (5 months) Mumbai Metropolitan Region

Honoured to be part of Board of Directors for Rotaract Club.

I'll be responsible for:

- 1.) Representing Rotaract Club of King's Circle Internationally
- 2.) Maintaining relationships with other Organizations glocally.
- 3.) Coordinating with other Rotaract Clubs globally.

All the aforementioned responsibilities are meant to serve society for greater collective good for all of us, especially the underprivileged.

Upwork

1 year 7 months

Rising Talent Freelancer

June 2019 - Present (1 year 3 months)

I was selected to be a part of Rising Talent program given demonstration of my strong performance in a short duration of time.

Freelancer

February 2019 - June 2019 (5 months)

I help clients with branding solutions mainly revolving around graphic designing, marketting & business development.

Harvard Business Review Member of HBR Ascend Select

January 2020 - Present (8 months)

My responsibilities and roles as a HBR Ascend Select Member are to shape the culture, content and the way HBR readers learn from us.

I'll need to work on different research projects led by HBR Ascend.

Quora

Quora Partner

June 2019 - Present (1 year 3 months)

India

I was invited by Quora to join Quora Partner Program. My main responsibility is to ensure our (Quora's) existing users and upcoming users have interesting, interactive and useful Content for them by Best Writers.

Clarity FI, LLC
Marketing Analyst
February 2019 - Present (1 year 7 months)

Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, United States (Remote)

I am associated with Clarity FI, LLC as 'Aspiring Entrepreneur, Marketing Analyst & Problem Solver'. Clarity FI, LLC is a US-Based consulting firm. Clarity FI offers complete done-for-you business financial management, accounting, bookkeeping, reporting, consulting and analysis.

I accept event management and marketing assignments from Mr. David Wagstaff, Founder & Managing Principal.

Creative Guns International Business Development Manager June 2020 - July 2020 (2 months)

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Being a IBD Manager at Creative Guns is a privilege. First, it's all remote.

I get to work with a diverse global team including Mr. Priyadarshi, Serial

Entrepreneur & founder at Creative Guns, Mr. Sadhak Mandal & Mr. Ankit Lal,
one of the best digital marketeers in country. So good.

My responsibilities include:

- 1. Lead Generation
- 2. Research about prospects
- 3. Approaching prospects
- 4. Looking for strategic partnership opportunities
- 5. Proposal drafting
- 6. Negotiations
- 7. Closing..
- 8. And pretty much everything I could do to ensure Creative Guns is one of the best Globally in next few years.

If you have any requirement of any sort of marketing or branding services, you know where to find me.

Saad@thecreativeguns.com

E-Cell, ICT Mumbai 11 months

Contingent Leader January 2020 - April 2020 (4 months) Mumbai Area, India It was a wonderful Journey from team building to unforgettable moments, we cherished together. I had a sour throat but a great time leading the young & enthusiastic team of E-cell ICT.

We made it to top 10 in most of the Competitons out of 50-200 teams.

PR Head

June 2019 - April 2020 (11 months)

Mumbai Area, India

E-cell, ICT Mumbai is an initiative to further nourish Entrepreneurial Culture of ICT, which boasts of 500+ first generation Entrepreneurs.

I, being PR Head, will take this to next level by ensuring mass participation.

I'm responsible for

Public Relations

Social Media Marketing

Handling Social media handles including Facebook, Instagram, LinkedIn and Whatsapp.

E-mail Marketing

Contacting E-cell members from other Colleges to bring more participants.

I'm also enjoying the aspect of hosting all the events of E-cell ICT Mumbai. I really enjoy public speaking and improving my communication skills.

Event Head at Pitchers

December 2019 - January 2020 (2 months)

Mumbai Area, India

Leading a team of coordinators & volunteers for Senior Pitchers, an event meant for Real Startups to come forward & pitch their ideas to incubation centers, Investors & probable Collaborators.

Senior Pitchers is a flagship Event of Entrepreneurship Summit of E-cell ICT. I'm grateful we made it go beyond mark. We got teams from all over the Nation. Many teams got funding & incubation offers.

Youth Parliament Program (YPP)
Leadership Delegate
February 2020 - February 2020 (1 month)

Hyderabad Area, India

Selected as one of the 100 delegates across the Nation to attend the Leadership Bootcamp organised by Youth Parliament Program. The 3 day residential program aims to encourage contribution of Youth in policy making

via dailogue with IAS officers, MPs, MLAs & other Ministers. I'm glad, I went there.

I learnt a lot about:

- 1. Leadership
- 2. Policy Making
- 3. Role of Governments
- 4. Taxation
- 5. Education Sector

I've voice notes if you need. Just ping me.

Harvard US-India Initiative
Delegate
December 2019 - January 2020 (2 months)
Mumbai Area, India

I am glad to share that I was selected among the brightest and talented Delegates globally. I attended Harvard Conference 2020 with other Amazing Delegates from USA, Malaysia, Singapore, UK, etc.

This has been a phenomenal Networking platform. It has impacted me beyond my imagination. Worth it.

VORTEX 7.O, Asia's Largest Chemfest Winner of Jr. IDP October 2019 - October 2019 (1 month) Mumbai Area, India

It was a very thrilling journey from several sleepless nights to overnight victory.

Jr. IDP is one of the flagship events of VORTEX.

It tests our Engineering skills like technical knowledge and problem solving skills.

It begins with open ended Case Studies publicly available Nationwide inviting solutions from Participants.

Z Nation Lab Ideathon Co-ordinator March 2019 - March 2019 (1 month) Mumbai, Maharashtra, India In collaboration with Z-Nation labs and JITO IIF, VEF conducted an Ideathon program on 15th - 16th March 2019 at NESCO, Goregaon.

The event was a 2 days entrepreneur's boot-camp. The theme was IDEA - BUILD - LAUNCH.

My responsibilities included ensuring proper execution of the event and assisting Event Head for success of event. This was a great experience for me as I learnt more about Entrepreneurship and Event Management. I also networked with great Investors and Entrepreneurs. Made friends & had lots of fun:)

Internshala Internshala Student Partner November 2018 - February 2019 (4 months) Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

My responsibilities included creating awareness about various internships offered by Internshala through social media marketing, guiding students about the same, etc.

E-Cell, IIT Bombay Top 5 January 2019 - January 2019 (1 month) Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

I Participated in 'Game of Thrones', a stimulated trading competition, secured a rank in top 5.

Himalaya Vidya Mandir Senior Secondary Public School Red House Captain July 2016 - July 2017 (1 year 1 month) Haldwani Area, India

I was the youngest House Captain till date. Under my leadership, we won most of the intra-school competitions.

Himalaya Vidya Mandir Senior Secondary Public School Prefect July 2012 - July 2013 (1 year 1 month)

Haldwani Area, India

Education

Institute Of Chemical Technology BE - Bachelor of Engineering, Chemical Engineering · (2018 - 2022)

Himalya Vidya Mandir Senior Secondary School

12th CBSE Board , Science with Physical Education and English

· (2017 - 2018)

Himalaya Vidya Mandir Senior Secondary Public School
High School (10th), Science, Mathematics, Social Sciences, Hindi & English
· (2015 - 2016)